bravejournal.com 2019-12-15

# Bravenet Privacy Policy

Introduction

Bravenet cares about its site visitors and users.  We are want to make sure that their personal information is protected, and that any use of that information is in compliance with applicable privacy laws and regulations.  We are not in the business of selling personal information about our customers, members and users. We use information shared with us for the purpose of running and improving our products and Services and in that capacity may operate as a data controller and, to the extent we process data, a data processor.

This Privacy Policy  explains how Bravenet might collect, use and disclose personal information, as well as the related rights and options that are available to our site visitors and users.

Please read our Privacy Policy, and make sure that you understand what is set out below, before you use or access any of our Products Services.  Capitalized terms which are not defined herein shall have the meaning ascribed to them in our [Terms of Service.](https://www.bravenet.com/terms.php)

Scope

This Privacy Policy is effective with respect to any data that we have collected, collect or receive, about and/or from you, according to our [Terms of Service](https://www.bravenet.com/terms.php).

Information Bravenet Collects

a. Information We Collect Directly From You: We collect personal information from you when you use our Products and Services; the type of information that we collect from you depends on your particular interaction with our Products and Services. We require you to register to access certain features; we may collect the following information from you during the registration process: your name, country of residence, address, phone number, email address, and a password that you select.

If you choose to purchase one of our paid Products and Services, we may also collect your billing information, in order to process the transaction. Billing information includes your name, address, telephone number, credit card details, PayPal email address, and other information necessary to process the transaction.Currently, We retain the first and last 4 digits of your credit card number, credit card type, name, address, and some other billing information, so that you may identify that card used in the future. Bravenet does not store your full credit card number or CVV2; this information is discarded after your transaction has been processed.

If your subscription is auto-renewing, we will store your payment information on our secure servers for as long as necessary to carry out the terms of your subscription.

All transactions are processed over an industry standard SSL/TLS connection, with a minimum of 128-bit encryption.

b. Information We Collect About You Automatically: We and our third party service providers, use cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies to collect information about you automatically as you use some of our Products and Services. Examples of this type of information include, but are not limited to, the dates and times of your use of a particular service or product and the route by which you choose to access it, including your IP (Internet Protocol) address, the type of browser and operating system you use, or domain name, and your use of any hyperlinks or downloadable content available through our Products and Services. We may combine this information with other information that we collect about you. Please see “Cookies and Tracking Technologies” below for more information.

c. Cookies and Tracking Technologies: Bravenet and its affiliates, partners, and service providers (such as marketing, analytics, and customer support partners) may use cookies, pixels, and similar technologies for analyzing trends, site administration, understanding how users interface with our Products and Services  and to gather demographic information about our customers and users. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and in an aggregated basis.

By using our Products and Services with your browser set to accept cookies, you are agreeing and consenting to our use of cookies and other technologies tho provide our Products and Services.  You can control the use of certain cookies at the individual browser level or in your operating system preferences.

Cookies are used for a variety of reasons, some of which are strictly necessary for the Products and services to work properly.  If you opt-out of such cookies, you may still use many of our Products and Services, but your ability to use some features or areas may be limited.

We partner with third parties to either display advertising on our Service or to manage our advertising on other sites, such as Facebook. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on our Service and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/&sa=D&ust=1527271666296000).  You can control Facebook ad preferences using Settings in your Facebook account.

Information that Bravenet Customers Provide us About You. 

We may also collect similar information pertaining to visitors and users of our customers’ websites or services solely for and on our customers’ behalf, and at their direction.  An example might be a case where one of our clients might import a list of email addresses for use in our mailing list service.  The email addresses and other contact information that our customer provides us would be stored with Bravenet on the customers behalf.

In cases like this, our customer is the data controller, and Bravenet is a data processor.  As a data processor, we do not have a direct relationship with the person whose personal information we collect and process at the direction of our customer.  If you are a user of one of these Bravenet customers and no longer want to be contacted by that customer, please contact the Bravenet customer you interacted with directly.

You have the right to access and change the personal information we collect and process as a data processor.  An individual who seeks to access or to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate personal information should direct their request to the Bravenet customer who is the data controller, rather than to Bravenet directly. 

If you are one of our Customers who is a data controller, you are responsible for complying with all laws and regulations that may apply to the collection and control of the information you collect, including all privacy and data protection laws of all relevant jurisdictions.  You are also responsible for the security, integrity and authorized usage of that information.  It is your responsibility to obtain appropriate informed consent for the collection and use of the information.

In particular, if you’re located in the European Economic Area (EEA) or collect or use information through our Products and Services that relates to anyone in the EEA, you represent and warrant that in using our Products and Services, and in collecting the information, you:

Will clearly describe in writing how you plan to use any data collected, including for your use of our Products and Services. You’ll get express consent to transfer data to Bravenet and be processed, and you’ll otherwise comply with whatever privacy policy you have posted.

Have complied, and will comply, with all regulations, as well as data protection, electronic communication, and privacy laws that apply to the countries where you’re operating or where your users reside.

Have collected, stored, used, and transferred all data relating to any individual in compliance with all data protection laws and regulations. You have the necessary permission to allow Bravenet to receive and process data and send communications to that individual on your behalf.

Agree to indemnify and hold Bravenet harmless from any losses, including attorney fees, that result from your breach of any part of these warranties.

Have agreed to our Terms of Service, and to the terms set out in this Privacy Policy.

5\. How Bravenet Uses your Information 

We collect information to provide and operate the Products and Services, including:

To customize and improve our Services, based on our customers’ and users’ experiences, and to develop new products based on their preferences;To provide our customer and users with assistance and technical support;

To be able to contact our customer and users with general or personalized service-related notices and promotional messages;

To diagnose and prevent service or technology problems reported by our customers users or staff ;

For research, analytics, assessing patterns of use, planning and assessing marketing initiatives by Bravenet;

To create aggregated statistical data and other aggregated and/or inferred Non-personal Information, which we or our business partners may use to provide and improve our respective services;

To improve our data security and fraud prevention capabilities;

To comply with any applicable laws and regulations.

​

We will only use your Personal Information, (which is defined as information that identifies an individual or may with reasonable efforts cause the identification of an individual, or may be of private or sensitive nature), where we are satisfied that:

our use of your Personal Information is necessary to perform a contract or take steps to enter into a contract with you (e.g. to provide you with a website builder, to provide you with our customer assistance and technical support), or

our use of your Personal Information is necessary to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we have, or

our use of your Personal Information is necessary to support legitimate interests that we have as a business (for example, to maintain and improve our Services by identifying user trends and the effectiveness of Wix campaigns and identifying technical issues), provided it is conducted at all times in a way that is proportionate, and that respects your privacy rights.

6\. ​Marketing Communications. 

By using Bravenet’s Products and Services, you agree and consent to receive marketing communications from Bravenet or any of its affiliates or partners. To the extent you have not already done so during sign-up, you may select not to receive from Bravenet or any of our partners certain email related to marketing, promotions or newsletters by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these email or by [unsubscribing here](http://www.bravenet.com/unsub.php). You may also notify us through our help center, by email at abuse@bravenet.com or by mail at P.O. Box 1722 Suite 100 - 180 McCarter Street, Parksville, BC, Canada V9P 2H5.

7\. Mailing Lists

a. Members Update, Tips and Tricks, Freebies and Special Offers mailing lists:

When registering a Bravenet account, you may agree to subscribe to our Members Update, Tips and Tricks, Resources, Freebies or Special Offers mailing lists. These lists may contain third-party sponsorships. You may unsubscribe from these mailing lists at any time by removing your email address here: [Unsubscribe](http://www.bravenet.com/unsub.php).

You have the following options for removing your information from our database to not receive future communications or to terminate your Bravenet account.

All mailing lists have unsubscribe instructions contained at the bottom of the email.

You can go to the Support Center to contact Bravenet support.

You can login to the Members Area here and delete your account.

You can login to the Members Area here to change any information previously provided.

b. Mailing List Service

When you register to use our Mailing List Services, you must abide by all applicable legislation relating to the proper collection and use of email addresses. We will neither use, nor disclose the email addresses or personal information of your subscribers to any third party unless we are compelled by law or, in our sole discretion, whenever we believe an emergency, illegal activity or some other reasonable basis exists for notifying or providing such information to the appropriate authorities.

8\. Public Services

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, classified ads, and guestbooks available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

9\.  Children under 18

Our Services are not permitted to children less than 18 years of age.  No one under age 18 should provide any Personal Information to us through any of our Services.  We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 18. Parents and guardians should supervise their children's activities at all times.

10\.  Storing Data

Information we collect, receive and maintain may be processed and stored by Bravenet and our authorized affiliates in Canada, and in other jurisdictions as needed to properly deliver our Products and Services, or to carry out any legal requirements.

Bravenet is located in Canada.  Canada is a recognized global leader in privacy standards, and was the first non-European country to be granted Adequacy Status under the European Union Data Protection Directive for protection of Personal Information of EU Member State residents.

Bravenet affiliates and service providers that store or process Personal Information on our behalf are all contractually committed to keep it protected and secure, and may not make any unauthorized use of the information.

Upon request Bravenet will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your Personal Information by opening a Support Ticket here: https://www.bravenet.com/help/postquestion.php

​

Please note that permanently deleting your Bravenet account erases all of your information from our databases (to the extent allowable by law). After completing this process, you will not be able use any of our Products and Services, and we will not be able to restore your account or retrieve your data in the future.  You would have to start from scratch.

11\. Disclosing your Data to 3rd Parties

Third Party Services: 

Bravenet has partnerships with a few carefully chosen service providers, whose solutions complement, facilitate and enhance our Products and Services, including domain name registrars, hosting and server co-location services, Internet Service Providers (ISPs), content delivery networks, data and cyber security services, transaction processing services, fraud detection and prevention services, web analytics, e-mail distribution and monitoring services, session recording and remote access services, performance measurement, data optimization and marketing services, content providers, and our legal and financial advisors (collectively, “3rd Party Service(s)”). 

Such 3rd Party Services may receive or otherwise have access to our customers’ and users’ Personal Information,  as well as our customers’ users’ Personal Information, to carry out their role in assisting us providing or enhancing our Products and Services, but they may only use it for such purposes.

You should be aware that, while our Products and Services may contain links to other websites or services, we are not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every website and service you visit before providing your Personal Information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these linked third -party websites and services.

Law Enforcement, Legal Requests and Duties:

Where permitted or required by local laws, including those related to data protection, Bravenet may disclose or provide access to your Personal Information pursuant to a legal request, such as a court order, search warrant or subpoena, or in compliance with applicable laws, if we believe that we are required by law, with or without notice to you or consent.

Protecting Others:

If Bravenet has a good faith belief that doing so will help protect the safety, property or rights of others (including other customers, users and Bravenet staff), we may share your Personal Information with or without notice to you.

Social Media Features and Framed Pages:

Bravenet’s Products and Services include some social media features and widgets, single sign on features, such as the “Facebook Connect” or “Google Sign-in”, the “Facebook Like” button, the “Share this” button or other interactive mini-programs .These social media features may collect information such as your IP address or which web page you are visiting, and may set cookies to enable them to function properly. Social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Products and Services. Your interactions with these third parties’ social media features are governed by their policies and not ours.

Also, our Products and Services may allow you to share your personal information with third parties directly, such as through web page framing methods that serve content  to serve content from Third Party Services or other parties, while retaining the general look and feel of our Products and Services (“Web Frames”). If you decide to interact or share any personal information through these Web Frames, you are providing it to these third parties and not to Bravenet, and this is governed by the third parties’ policies and not Bravenet’s.

Affiliated Companies:

We may share Personal Information with affiliated companies, including  Viviti Technologies, Inc., whicha also operates as Jigsy.com and VivitiCMS.com. 

12\.  Retention and Security of your Information. 

We will retain your information for as long as your Bravenet account is active or as needed to provide the Products and Services to you. We will also retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. These measures include secure servers, encrypted passwords, and other security measures to guarantee the privacy of our members. We do not store credit card information on any Bravenet servers.

13\.  Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time. All updates and amendments are effective immediately upon notice, which we may give by any means, including, but not limited to, by posting a revised version of this Privacy Policy or other notice on our website. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy often to stay informed of changes that may affect you, as your continued use of the website (and/or any other Products and Services) signifies your continuing consent to be bound by this Privacy Policy. 

14\. Questions & Concerns

For questions or comments, or if you want to update, delete, or change any Personal Information we hold, or if you have a concern about a specific privacy matter, please send us a message through our[ ](https://www.bravenet.com/help/postquestion.php)[Support Center](https://www.bravenet.com/help/postquestion.php). You may also contact us by postal mail at:

Bravenet Web Services Inc.

Attn. Privacy Officer

P.O. Box 1722 Suite 100 - 180 McCarter Street 

Parksville, BC, Canada V9P 2H5
